Hey everyone, and thanks for dropping
back into the equityverse.
Today, we're going to talk about SpaceX
and how it has retraced the IPO gains.
If you guys like the content, make sure
you subscribe to the channel, give the
video a thumbs up, and also check out
the sale on Into the Cryptoverse Premium
at intothecryptoverse.com.
We put out a video
last week when SpaceX launched, and one
of the things we we talked about a lot
is how what often happens when you have
IPOs is that there'll be this initial
surge in price,
and then often times,
um
I believe approximately 90%, although
I'm not 100% sure about that that
statistic, but I think about 90%
of a lot of the IPOs do eventually do
eventually trade below where they opened
up at, and we talked about that last
week, and you know, sure enough, not
even a week later, SpaceX gave back all
the IPO gains.
And so, this is the SpaceX chart.
There's not really a whole lot to work
with. In fact, this is one of the few
times where it might make sense to look
at like 4-hour charts just because we
don't really have a lot of data,
but
what's remarkable is just how frequently
IPOs do this, right? They go up, there's
the initial surge and hype,
we give it all back, and then we figure
out like what the actual so,
quote-unquote fair value is of of the
company.
Now,
we made a comparison to the Tesla IPO.
Now, the first thing I'll say, and I I
believe I said in the video back then,
is that
the market cap of SpaceX at launch,
no pun intended, is a lot higher than
the market cap of Tesla when it
launched.
Be that as it may, I still think that
SpaceX could be just as disruptive
disruptive as Tesla if not more so
eventually.
When we were looking at the Tesla
launch, we said, "Well, why why compare?
Why make the comparison at all?"
Well, they're both run they're both the
the CEO of both companies
um founder Well, I guess not
of SpaceX, but the person who runs both
companies
Elon Musk.
When did the IPOs launch?
June. Right? You have June 12th of 2026
for SpaceX and for Tesla, it was
June 29th of 2010.
So, both run by Elon Musk. IPOs that
both launched in June.
Also, the IPOs were launched in June of
a midterm year. So, 2026 for SpaceX
for
Tesla.
So, a lot of up similarities. And and
the similarities continue in the sense
that after Tesla launched
um
after we had the the the launch here by
by Tesla, what happened is we got this
move up
to the tune from the launch, it went up
about 60%.
Okay, about 60%. Now, what's interesting
is from the launch of SpaceX
so, if you look at SpaceX, how far did
it go up?
About 50%. But again,
the market cap's different. It takes
exponentially more money to move the
market cap of SpaceX than Tesla when
they were launched because the market
cap of Tesla was just so much lower.
A counterpoint to that is the money
supply is up a lot from from back then.
So, while the market cap's maybe
different and they still are different
when you adjust for inflation
you know, things do trend up over time.
At least good assets trend up over time.
So, you have SpaceX going up 50% at
launch.
Tesla going up 60.
And then
the similarities continue. And And we'll
talk about where they may eventually
differ.
After
the Tesla IPO, we went below that
4 days later. And then we found a low
5 days later.
And from the high
Tesla dropped
50%.
Now, you look at SpaceX and as measured
from the high, it's dropped about
34%.
And it did it
over the course of about 4 to 5 days.
Right? Maybe a little bit longer. It
took six bars, I guess.
But there are a lot of similarities
between these two launches. Now,
here's where it could start to differ.
And And you know, depending on what IPOs
you're looking at, they they play out in
a very different
format or they they play out in a very
differently.
But essentially what I said is that, you
know,
to expect the first pop in SpaceX to
fade back down to the IPO lows.
And then from there, you'll likely see
SpaceX try to form a low. Now, when you
think about every stock, you have to
think about the idiosyncratic risk of
that stock and the market risk. Let's go
see what What was
uh the S&P doing?
Um
Let's go see what the S&P 500 was doing
back in 2010. Okay, because we've
obviously made some sort of
provided some thoughts about what the
S&P might do this year.
In 2010,
what you'll see is the S&P had a a small
correction,
very small correction,
at the very beginning of the year, about
a 9% drop. We then had another
correction sort of in the middle part of
the year.
And then we had a large move up from a
July low.
So, from a July low, where the July low
took out the February low.
You see that? The July low in 2010 took
out the February low. So, when you think
about how Tesla played out,
the low that was formed in July
corresponded to the S&P putting in a
low,
and the low for the S&P was a lower low
compared to February. And then
there was another correction, but it
didn't occur until the next year.
But you see that?
Look at how and I know the nuances are
are, you know, somewhat tricky, but
the
the low in in the early part of the year
the year, January, February, we took out
that low
in the S&P in late June, early July. And
when we took out that low, that is where
Tesla bottomed. And Tesla never went
below that low ever again.
But one of the reasons it never went
below that low ever again
is because when you look at the S&P,
the S&P also actually never went below
that low.
And that's been 16 years ago.
Now,
where are we today? Okay. So, today the
S&P put in a low in March,
but the S&P
is nowhere near taking out that low,
right? So, the idiosyncratic risk is
there, but the market risk is a little
bit different, right? Because often
times there is a larger correction at
some point kind of going into the back
half of the year.
In 2010, that correction actually
occurred uh starting in in late April,
early May. Right? That's when we had
that like 17% drop. And that was after
an initial
10% drop.
In 2026, we had about a 10% drop, but we
haven't really had a second drop. Not
yet.
Now, if you look at 2014, you'll see
something similar. There was a drop at
the beginning of the year
that was about, say, 6%. The drop later
in the year was about 10.
In 2018, the first drop in the beginning
of the year of the mid-term year was
about 12. The second drop later in the
year was about 20. And in la- in 2022,
you can see the first drop. You could
argue like 14, 15% all the way up to
even 24% of depending on how far you go.
And then the second big drop was about
20% as well. So, I think the argument
here is that it's not yet clear if we've
had that second drop yet in the S&P 500.
And I don't really think we've had we've
we've had it yet.
A lot of times you'll see the S&P find a
local top in the second half of the
year. Sometimes it could go on until
September. In 2018, I believe it was
Yeah, it was it was September where the
market topped. In 2014, it was also
September before you had a larger drop.
Right? You like you had a very brief
pullback into August. And then a larger
drop later in the year.
So, I guess the point is is to say as it
relates to SpaceX is
the market it's not exactly the same
setup as 2010. But what I would say is
that like 2010,
whatever the price ends up doing, you
could argue that in the back half of the
year, it was a fairly good accumulation
zone for Tesla
even though it didn't move for years.
And and that's the reality is, you know,
it it it obviously looking back on it
now, it was a great accumulation zone.
But you have to also keep in mind that
that spike we had on the IPO launch day,
we didn't durably get above that level
and not look back until 2 and 1/2 years
later.
So, I think it would be prudent for
people to kind of recognize, "Hey,
this might take a while. And also, you
know, we're likely going to see
prices stay somewhat suppressed for the
rest of the year in alignment with the
second half of the year midterm
weakness. Now, if the S&P 500 were to
drop and say take out the March low, or
if it were to get even bigger drop and
say drop like 20% from that level, I
could see SpaceX forming a low that then
holds for a a, you know, for a really
long time.
But, because we haven't really had that
yet, it's not yet clear if that is the
case. Uh but, I would say this, over the
long haul, I do not recommend bet
betting against against Elon Musk.
I just the the first video I put out my
SpaceX,
I just wanted to caution people that
were FOMOing into this rally and to say,
"Look, guys, a lot of times we give back
these IPO gains."
Okay? And this is what happens a lot of
times. And and we've done it again. Now,
there are some IPOs that continue to
bleed for a while. Like, they don't
Like, we compare to Tesla, if you look
at and I'm just looking at successful
companies, right? Like, if you're just
looking at at some of these successful
companies that have existed
and still do. Like, Apple is a good
example of an IPO where obviously
Apple has been incredibly successful.
You had a surge after the IPO, you had a
drop, and then it dropped further
because we ended up getting a recession.
But, it didn't it didn't really matter
as time went on. You could argue that in
in this case, uh
Apple launched at the very end of 1980.
Let's just call it early 1981 cuz it was
essentially early It was a very, very
end of 1980.
And then it bottomed
um about 18 months later.
Okay? But again, with Apple, you would
argue that this entire window right here
was a fairly good accumulation zone
for Apple.
So, when you think about IPO launches,
usually what happens is you rally,
you then come out, come back down, and
take out the IPO levels, and then you
get another rally.
And then you get another drop.
Look at Apple. With Apple, it was IPO
rally, sweep the low, lower high,
recession, and then the rest is history.
For Tesla,
for Tesla, it was rally up, sweep the
low, rally up again, and then it was a
higher low, but there was also no
recession, right? So, you see the
difference. So, what I would argue here
with SpaceX is, you know, you're
sweeping the low now.
Could take a little bit of time, like it
doesn't have to happen over a day, could
be could happen over a couple of weeks.
You'll likely see another rally,
and then from there, whether it's a
higher high or lower high, will will
probably help us figure out if maybe the
low at the end of the year is a higher
low or a lower low.
And again, I I don't have the answer for
you on that. I'm just looking at at like
how these trends tend to play out, and
usually with IPOs, you rally, you give
it back, you go a little below the IPO
price, you rally again, and then
depending on if it's a higher high or
lower high, we'll then kind of
and regardless of whether it's a higher
high or lower high, you will likely get
one more pullback later in the year that
would align with the correction, the
sort of the back half of the year
midterm correction with the S&P 500. And
that, I think, you know, will continue
to offer opportunities. I do not
recommend, again, betting against Elon
Musk. For me, I will look to accumulate
SpaceX, especially in the second half of
this year. It's not financial advice. I
just, you know, I I got really bullish
on Tesla a long time ago and and it took
a long time for the market to ever care
and then eventually it went up. And I
think SpaceX is going to go through
something similar. There's going to be
some fear about whether it's going to
ever be profitable
stuff like that, but I think in you
know, when you look back on this in 20
years, it's going to be very disruptive.
Even though in the short term, it might
not appear as as obvious. So, those are
my thoughts on SpaceX. Hopefully the
video that we put out last week was
helpful
uh in in keeping people sort of on the
right side of this sort of FOMO rally.
Um but those are my thoughts about
SpaceX. If you guys like the content,
make sure you subscribe, give the video
a thumbs up and again, check out the
sale on ITCPREMIUM at
intothecryptoverse.com. I'll see you
guys next time. Bye.